## **The Interactive Resume**

## **MD TAMZID HASAN**

North South University

Bashundhara R/A

Dhaka- 1229, Bangladesh

tamzid.hasan@northsouth.edu

+880 1711 927924

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

## **Objective**

To build up a career in public health and development, including research. Experienced in developing and preparing tools, data collection, data sorting, updating the database, and preparing project budgets based on research demand. Multitasking, solid team-building capacity, strong leadership, and interpersonal communication skills.

## **Experience**

Experience	
Jhpiego Bangladesh Project on Maternal Immunization Readiness Initiative.	Consultant January 2023 to February 2023
Jhpiego Bangladesh	Contributor
Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool (HFRA) for Maternal Immunization (MI).	March 2023 to January 2024
North South University Myopia and dry-eye disease among the female students	Thesis
of NSU.	November 2023
NSU Global Health Institute People's perception, experience, and usage of health	Qualitative Data Collector
facilities.	November 2023
NSU Global Health Institute USAID's Community-Health-Systems Strengthening	Research Assistant
Activity (CHSS).	October 2023
North South University	Project
PTSD, Insomnia, and Suicidal Ideation among the firefighters.	September 2023
North South University NSU Global Health Institute (NGHI)	Research Assistant August 2022 to December 2023
Chalmers University of Technology High Voltage Converter Transformer using Non-	Project
destructive Methods.	October 2018
Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for using in PV	Thesis
system.	June 2018
S. S. Engineering & Construction Builders, developers, & construction.	Electrical Engineer October 2013 to July 2017

Assistant Engineer

November 2011 to July 2012

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd Renewable energy system

#### **Education**

MPH in Epidemiology North South University 2021 – 2022

Masters in EPE Chalmers University of Technology 2017 -

BSc in EEE Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology 2006 – 2011

### **Honors & Scholarships**

University scholarship for MPH program

North South University

International student scholarship for master's program in
Sweden

Adlerbert Foreign Student
Hospitality Foundation

Scholarship awarded to attend the study session of Peace in

the Spotlight in Strasbourg, France.

Council of Europe

Scholarship awarded to attend the project management training in the frame of Peers to Peace in Athens, Greece.

Erasmus+ Scholarship

## **Scientific Work**

#### Journal Publication

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Syed Sharaf Ahmed Chowdhury, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Inequalities in early initiation of breastfeeding in Bangladesh: An estimation of relative and absolute measures of inequality*. International Breastfeeding Journal. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1186/s13006-023-00584-y">https://doi.org/10.1186/s13006-023-00584-y</a>

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Md. Habib Naziat, Tahmina Zerin, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Permanent, long-acting, and short-acting reversible contraceptive methods use among women in Bangladesh: An analysis of Bangladesh Demographic and Health Survey 2017-2018 data.* BMJ Open 2023;13:e073469. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2023-073469

Md Jakaria Rahimi, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Ripan Kumar Dhar, Md Shaheer Ibne Islam, Khatune Jannat Siddiqua, and Shahriar Azgar (2011): *Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for Photovoltaic System*. IJETSE International Journal of Emerging Technologies in Science and Engineering, Vol.5, No.2, Dec 2011.

# **Volunteering Work**

#### **Activities**

CERIA Farm International Work Camp in Ipoh, Perak at Malaysia.

SCI Malaysia

International Work Camp IN-SCI 11.10 on Achalam Eco ashram- From Ego to Eco (EE01) in Tiruvannamalai, Tamil Nadu at India.

SCI India & SCI Hong Kong

International Work Camp NP-SCI 13.4 on Help in Reconstruction of SCI Nepal School Building in Balthali, Panauti at Nepal.

International Work Camp BD-SCI 11.5 on Climate & Sustainable

Lifestyle with River Erosion Affected Community in Shibchar, SCI Bangladesh

Madaripur.

International Work Camp BD-SCI 10.2 on Environment Protection in SCI Bangladesh

Kuakata, Patuakhali, Barisal.

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

Regional Work Camp BD-SCI 11.3 on Peace in Khalia, Rajoir,	SCI Bangladesh
Madaripur.	

International Work Camp BD-SCI 13.1 on Physiotherapy Camp at Rehabilitation Centre for in GUP, Rajoir, Madaripur.

SCI Bangladesh

## **Membership**

Member of Public Health Association of Bangladesh (PHAB).	2022
Member of Public Health and Science Club, North South University.	2021
Vice President of ANIMESH a social organization.	2021
Reception Host- 2018 of Chalmers Studentkårs Arbetsmarknardsdagar (CHARM), Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden.	2018
General Secretary of Göteborg Universella Kulturförening (GUKF) a community base non-profit organization at Gothenbug, Sweden.	2018 to 2020
Member of The Institution of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB). <i>Memership No. M/34701</i> .	2012
Volunteer Coordinator of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2015
Member of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2007

# **Contact Information**

### Md. Tamzid Hasan

Campus Address
Plot- 15, Block- B,
Bashundhara R/A,
Dhaka-1229, Bangladesh
tamzid.hasan@northsouth.edu

Permanent Address
House- 268, Flat- C4,
Jafrabad, West Dhanmondi,
Dhaka-1207, Bangladesh
https://www.tamzid.info

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info